

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Project Manager seeking roles in Program Management, Portfolio Management, Infrastructure Management, PMO Management, Stakeholder Management, Data Centre Migration, IT Transformation, Agile

Methodology, Recruitment, Confluence, Waterfall, Prince2, JIRA, SDLC, ITIL

Current Designation: Lead Project Manager

Current Company: BMC Software

Current Location: Pune

 ${\it Pref.\,Location:\,Bengaluru\,/\,Bangalore,} Hyderabad, Pune$

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Role: Program Mgr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

 $Key Skills: Project/Program \ Manager, Program \ Management, Portfolio \ Management, Infrastructure \ Management, PMO \ Management, PMO$

Total Experience: 15 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Management, Stakeholder Management, Data Centre Migration, IT Transformation, Agile

Methodology, Recruitment, Confluence, Waterfall, Prince 2, JIRA, SDLC, ITIL

Verified : L Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Enterprising & Resourceful IT Professional, offering 14 years of experience in Program Management and Service Delivery in SDLC.

Infrastructure and Data Centre Migration Projects across the Career

Managed team of Project Managers in India, monitored and supervised day-to-day functions in PMO, formulated Product Development, Project Roadmap to ensure satisfactory execution of Projects, Solution Document Review (Functional & Technical).

Service Delivery, Pre-Sales Support, Product Implementations & Support, RFP's Response, People Management and project completion

on time respectively

Supervised the Program Management/ Project Lifecycle functions defined under the process framework and managed projects/ programmes

in infrastructure and product based organizations, ensured Service Delivery and stakeholder deadlines were met within project budgets

Work Experience

BMC Software as Lead Project Manager Aug 2012 to Till Date

Growth Path:

Aug'12 to Sep'15 as Project Manager - (SaaS Business Operation)- Remedy On-Demand

Oct 15 to Sep 17 as Sr. Project Manager - (SaaS Business Operation) - Remedy On-Demand

Oct 17 to Sep'18 as Lead Project Manager - Z-Solutions - Common Services

Oct'18 to May'20 as Manager (Program Management)- R&D Program Management- Innovation Engine Process-PMO Jun'20 Onwards as Lead Project Manager - Z-Solutions - Common Services

Leading Program Management functions right from requirement analysis, coding, and testing (preparation of test cases along with

implementation) to the maintenance of proposed applications

Liaising with stakeholders during problem diagnosis, requirements gathering, detailed level design, development, system test, and product

development and implementation to ensure that optimal resolutions were achieved

Consulting and coordinating with projects teams, monitoring team progress, making sure projects are implemented in due time, and solving

technical issues

Directing end-to-end program management operations and ensuring qualitative service delivery and project completion on time

Analyzing the expectations of prospective clients, by obtaining Request for Quotation (RFQ's)/ Request for Inquiries (RFIs) and proposing business

solutions specific to the client to boost their business

Devising the corporate strategy and providing business consultancy for the organization's business operations;



Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. conceptualizing & developing new

business strategies which led to an increase in turnover & profitability of the clients

Developing project baselines, monitoring & controlling projects concerning cost, resource deployment, time overruns, and quality compliance to

ensure satisfactory execution of projects

Driving organizational objectives by successfully driving operational excellence, deploying innovative process automation solutions, building

strategic client communication plans, reducing cost, formulating SOPs, and enhancing skills of the team

Monitoring monthly metrics & KPIs, ensuring adherence to operational standards and consistently applying them; developing & monitoring

escalation processes to ensure that SLAs were achieved

Formulating project plans, estimating time requirements, establishing deadlines, monitoring milestones, tracking project lifecycle, reporting issues

that impact project progress including dashboard reporting and future engagement opportunities to both all internal BMC Stakeholders & top

management

Performing BMC PMO administration requirements, including:

- o Accurate revenue forecasting, monthly revenue closing
- o Management of project costs and margin
- o Precise project communications to (PMO and other internal stakeholders)
- o Working with resource management to make the best use of BMC resources for delivery
- o Following BMC's guidelines for revenue recognition
- Mphasis (An HP Company) as Project Manager (Data Centre Implementation and Infrastructure Projects)

May 2011 to Aug 2012

Completed Data Centre deployment for the client based in US and UK Led the Data Centre Mgration end-to-end Project Management from one location to another for a Swedish Client

Tulip Telecom Ltd. as Manager- Service Delivery , ROM Region Nov 2010 to May 2011

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Maharashtra Academy of Engineering & Education Research Medical College, Dabhade in 2006

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Diploma in Electronics Engineering SAFe 4.0 Agilist SAFe 4.0 Practitioner PMP

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
WINDOWS		
MS Office, Word, Excel, PowerPoint		
MS Projects, JIRA, Confluence, Remedy		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Marathi				
Kannada				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.